fbijobs.gov 2011-10-15

# Federal Bureau of Investigation

PRIVACY POLICY

Thank you for visiting the FBI Employment Web site and reviewing our privacy policy. Our privacy policy is clear: we will collect no personal information about you when you visit our website unless you choose to provide that information to us. Please review the following information to learn more about this site’s privacy policy and system security:

  * Authority
  * Privacy Act Notice
  * Information Collected and Stored Automatically
  * Site Security

* * *

**Authority**

The FBI investigates and assesses suitability and security issues of federal employment primarily under 5 U.S.C. §§ 3301 and 9101 and Executive Orders 10450 and 12968. The Director of the FBI exercises power and authority vested in the Attorney General to take final action on the employment, direction, and general administration of FBI personnel under 28 C.F.R. § 0.138. When the FBI requests your Social Security Account Number (SSAN) it does so under Executive Order 9397.

Back to Top

* * *

**Privacy Act Notice - Principal Purposes and Routine Uses of Employment Application Forms**

Pursuant to the Privacy Act of 1974, 5 U.S.C. §552a, we are providing the following information on the principal purposes and routine uses of information submitted on the FBI employment application forms.

The principal purpose of the forms is to collect information to determine the qualifications and suitability for FBI employment. Should you become an FBI employee, this information may be used to determine reassignments, reinstatements, transfers, or promotions. By law and regulation, we may evaluate your application to determine, for example, if you are entitled to Veterans' Preference, and if you are restricted by citizenship or residency requirements. We may also use your application to contact you for an interview and to verify your availability for employment as well as to collect information for an FBI background investigation to establish your eligibility for a required security clearance and for other authorized purposes within the Department of Justice. 

Your Social Security Account Number identifies you throughout your federal career, from job application to retirement. We may use your SSAN to accurately identify your records and to process your application for employment. We may also use your SSAN to seek information about you from employers, schools, banks, and other individuals who know you. In addition, your SSAN may be used to search for matches in other government files/databases (e.g., unpaid student loans, parent locators, etc.). Furthermore, all or part of your completed FBI application form may be disclosed outside the Department of Justice to the following: 

  * Federal agencies requesting lists of individuals who are eligible for appointment, reassignment, reinstatement, transfer, or promotion
  * State or local government agencies under either the Intergovernmental Personnel Act or the President's Executive Program when you have expressed an interest in such employment
  * Federal agency investigators to determine suitability for federal employment
  * Selecting officials who are involved with the internal personnel management of federal agencies
  * Appropriate federal, state, local, foreign, or other public authorities conducting criminal, intelligence, or security background investigations
  * Federal, state, or local agencies creating other personnel records after you have been appointed to an agency position
  * Appropriate entities responsible for licensing or for investigating, prosecuting, or enforcing law, regulation, or contracts
  * Federal, state, local, foreign, or other public authorities if there is a request for information on employment, security, contracting, or licensing determinations
  * The news media or general public when the disclosure of factual information would be in the public interest and could not reasonably be expected to constitute an unwarranted invasion of privacy 
  * Officials or employees of other federal agencies (including the White House) to assist in the performance of their duties
  * Non-FBI employees acting in furtherance of a Department of Justice function
  * Courts or adjudicative bodies when the FBI has an official interest in the proceedings
  * Authorized personnel pursuant to the routine uses most recently published in the Federal Register for the FBI's Central Records System (Justice/FBI-002), Bureau Personnel Management System (Justice/FBI-007) and Blanket Routine Uses (Justice/FBI-BRU)

Back to Top

* * *

**Information Collected and Stored Automatically**

If you do nothing during your visit but browse through the web site reading pages, viewing photographs, downloading information, etc., we will gather and store certain information about your visit automatically. The following information is automatically collected and stored about your visit: 

  * The Internet domain and Internet Protocol (IP) address from which you access our Web site
  * Your Internet Browser type and operating system of your computer
  * Date and time of your visit
  * Pages reviewed during your visit
  * If you linked to our Web site from another site, the address of that site

This information is primarily collected for statistical purposes. The FBI utilizes software programs to create summary statistics which are used to help make our site more useful to visitors (e.g., assessing what information is of most and least interest to visitors, determining the site's technical design specifications, identifying system performance or problem areas, etc.). In certain circumstances, however, we may take additional steps to identify you based on this information and we may share this information, including your identity, with other government agencies.

If you submit a resume online, the resume data you submit will be used as set forth under "Principal Purposes and Routine Uses." If you wish to submit your resume to another Federal agency outside of the FBI, you must submit it directly to that agency.

Back to Top

* * *

**Site Security**

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, various steps are utilized to protect information, such as: 

  * Firewalls - Firewalls block unauthorized access by individuals or networks and protect computer networks systems that interact with the Internet 
  * SSL Technology - We require that a "secure session" first be established, using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. Currently, we are using 128-bit encryption during SSL sessions
  * Network Monitoring (Security, Intrusion, and Detection) - For site security purposes, and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, all network traffic is monitored in order to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage or conduct criminal activity. To protect the system from unauthorized use and to ensure that the system is functioning properly, individuals using this computer system are subject to having all of their activities monitored and recorded by personnel authorized to do so by the FBI (and such monitoring and recording will be conducted). Anyone using this system expressly consents to such monitoring and is advised that if such monitoring reveals evidence of possible abuse or criminal activity, system personnel may provide the results of such monitoring to appropriate officials. Unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage to this service, are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under applicable federal law
  * Technology Advances - As advances in technology arise, this site is updated with software, patches, and fixes to ensure site stability
  * Virus Protection - Computer virus protection detects and prevents computer viruses from entering the systems. Our virus definitions are updated daily to ensure site stability

This system uses a session cookie so the user can view open positions, and enter data into a form on the site in order to apply for open FBI positions. This session cookie does not track any user data, and when the session is over it is rendered useless. When the user returns to the site, the user is issued another cookie with a random session ID that again becomes useless when the session is completed.

You may volunteer to provide us personally identifying information, for example, your mailing address, in an electronic mail message (i.e., email). Before you do so, you should know that the material you submit might be seen by various people. We may enter the information into a database and we may share it with other government agencies. It should be noted that e-mail is not necessarily secure against interception. If your communication is sensitive in nature, you may opt to send it by postal mail.

Back to Top

* * *
